# NIRAJ CHAVAN UI / Web Developer

**Email** - nirajd327@gmail.com **Phone** - +91 96071 95436

Splendour Greens Seetai Lake, 202, C Wing, Mulshi Road, Opposite Heera Garden, Bhugaon, Pune 412115

**Portfolio** - <a href="https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/">https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/</a>

Linkedin - https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

UI Developer with 5 years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites.

An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards.

Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR UI ENGINEER, XPANXION INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD.

Jan 2017 – Present, Location – Pune
Implementation of angular custom reusable
components, JWT token implementation, performance
optimization and API integration.

# UI DEVELOPER, CONNECT | 91 WEB SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

Dec 2015 - Jan 2017, Location – Pune
UI enhancement designs for better user experience,
convert PSD into HTML and make the websites
compatible with all browsers.

## WEB DEVELOPER, WHITECODE IT SOLUTION

July 2014 - Dec 2015, Location – Pune Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

# **SKILLS**

## **WEB TECHNOLOGIES –**

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, JQuery, Typescript, Angular 2/5/7, JSON, WordPress, Python, Flask, JHipster

# **VERSION CONTROL TOOLS -**

SVN, GIT

## DATABASE -

MySQL, PostgreSQL

# PROJECT TRACKING TOOLS -

Jira, Rally, Zoho, Trello

#### **BUILD TOOL -**

Webpack, NPM, Bower

## **TESTING FRAMEWORK TOOLS –**

Karma, Jasmine, Jest

# **EDUCATION**

## **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)**

**Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University** July 2011 – June 2014

# **DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING**

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Akurdi, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education)

July 2008 - May 2011

## SECONDRY SCHOOL EDUCATION

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board

June 2007 – July 2008

## PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: 07 August 1992

**MARITAL STATUS:** Unmarried

**NATIONALITY:** Indian

## **PERMANENT ADDRESS:**

At - Post - Tivare, Pali – Khopoli Rd, Taluka - Sudhagad, District - Raigad, Maharashtra, Pin Code - 410205

#### LANGUAGE KNOWN:

English, Marathi, Hindi

## PROJECT DETAILS -

**Project Name** – K7 SECURITY (Xpanxion)

Role – Senior UI Engineer

**Skills used** – HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Angular 7, Typescript, Karma, Jasmine, JHipster Framework

Team Size - 8

**Responsibility** - To build dashboard for end customers to manage multiple devices from online website account. Develop software solutions using industry best practices and in the area of security and performance in a web and architecture environment. Collaborates with team and business owners in the design and analysis phases as part of self-organizing feature teams. Maintain source-code repository, participate in Code Reviews, and conduct design reviews. Participate in deployment of code into production.

Project Name - SCOPERETAIL (Xpanxion)

Role – UI Engineer

Skills used – HTML 5, SASS, Bootstrap 4, Angular 5, Typescript, Karma, Jasmine

Team Size - 22

**Responsibility -** Design and developed UI Interface with optimized solution for E-commerce retail product. To create custom angular 5 components for Internal framework. To create UI mock-ups, wire frames and responsive design using HTML 5, Bootstrap 4 and JavaScript. Best solutions for performance optimization techniques and unit testing strategy. Build deployment strategy and micro web based service architecture. Integrated web rest API with front end application. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.

Project Name - ADA Accessibility (Xpanxion)

Role - UI Engineer

Skills used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Require JS, Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Docker for Windows

Team Size - 18

**Responsibility -** To make website compliance as per WCAG 2.0 standards. To give accessibility support for people who having temporary or situational disabilities. Mentor junior developers as required. Participate in peer code review.

**Project Name -** HOLLAND AMERICA LINE (https://www.hollandamerica.com/) (Xpanxion)

Role – UI Engineer

Skills used - HTML5, SCSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular 2, Bootstrap 3, Git, Rally,

Team Size - 6

**Responsibility** - Building modules of application, fetch data from database and integrate in application. To change functionality according to client requirement. Working closely with the product management team to understand user needs.

**Project Name -** CERTASLIM (https://www.certaslim.com/) (Connect | 91)

Role - UI Developer

**Skills used** – HTML5, SCSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Git, Jira

Team Size – 4

**Responsibility** - Design and develop high performance web applications using Front-end technologies. Use markup languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages. Develop new user-facing features. Build reusable code and libraries for future use. Create quality mockups and prototypes. Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability. Work closely with juniors and provide strong code reviews and feedback. Continually evaluate emerging frameworks and technologies to identify opportunities, trends and best practices that strengthen the development team.

Project Name – UITBIEDEN (https://www.uitbieden.nl/) (Connect | 91)

Role – UI Developer

**Skills used** – HTML 5, SCSS, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap 3, Bitbucket, Zoho

Team Size – 4

**Responsibility -** Work closely with UX team to illustrate design ideas using storyboards, sketch, process flow or graphic elements. Identify and troubleshoot UI multi browser responsive problems. Develop UI mockups, components and prototypes for mobile app, web or other digital forms. Conduct layout adjustment based on user

feedback. Prepare and present UI design to internal teams and key stakeholders. Adhere to style standards on fonts, colors and images.

Project Name - VIDEOTIER (https://www.videotier.com/) (Connect | 91)

Role - UI Developer

**Skills used** – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, SASS, Bootstrap, Photoshop

Team Size – 6

**Responsibility** - Will be responsible for designing layouts and mockups. Converting designing layouts into Responsive HTML5 sites. Designing sites for Mobiles and Web. Developing modular components that can be used across multiple sites. Integrating web services and implementing complex features.

Project Name - VARUN DESHMUKH & CO. (http://ddca.net.in/) (WhiteCode)

Role - Web Developer

Skills used – PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Team Size - 2

**Responsibility -** Work with Javascript and HTML, Work with JS testing frameworks to write tests to ensure high quality deliverables. Perform code reviews of your peers work. Utilise responsive design techniques Contribute to the design and architecture of enterprise products and features.

**Project Name -** SAISUKAMAL (http://www.saisukamal.com/) (WhiteCode)

Role - Web Developer

**Skills used** – PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap

Team Size - 3

**Responsibility** – Analyse, design and develop code. Perform maintenance on existing solutions. Provide innovative and cost-effective engineering solutions. Participate in knowledge sharing activities.

NIRAJ CHAVAN PLACE - PUNE